Poland Subject Files, Inclusive: 1947-2002, undated, Bulk: 1960-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Poland Subject Files
Inclusive: 1947-2002, undated, Bulk: 1960-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
14
Keston Institute, 1969 -
43 A4 document boxes
The Poland Subject Files contain a variety of materials on multiple topics pertaining to government, state policy, martial law, oppression, violence, censorship, international relations, opposition movements, dissidents, religion, religious persecution, and publications.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
Keston obtained materials from Poland starting in 1947. After the Yalta Conference, the Polish Provisional Government of National Unity was formed. Though there was Soviet domination in Poland at the time, many were unhappyDLsome believing that a third world war would defeat the Soviet Union. Elections were another source of unhappiness because of numerous claims of fraud due to Soviet Union control.
In the 1940’s following World War II, land was redistributed. The economy shifted from the wartime industrial basis to the Three-Year Plan of 1947 and the Six Year Plan of 1950. During this time, the government focused on employment and public education. As a result, adult illiteracy was almost eradicated and health care was easily accessible. Urbanization boomed and historic sites were rebuilt. Stalinization integrated propaganda into daily lives and public education.
After de-Stalinization in the Soviet Union in 1956, Edward Ochab became the First Secretary of the Polish United Workers’ Party and ushered in social reformation. His successor Wladyslaw Gomulka lessened dependence on the Soviet Union and formed ties with the Catholic Church in what became known as Polish October. Anti-Semitic factions within the Communist Party gained traction, and these ties created tension with remaining Polish Jews, most of whom were holocaust victims.
After the Marxist Revolution in 1965, the Conference of Polish Bishops wrote to German Bishops, and the two countries finally reconciled after the break following World War II. Protests mostly came in the form of art motivated by Prague Spring in Czechoslovakia. Academics, theatre, and education boomed.
After a series of price increases in the 1970s, workers revolted, and Edward Gierek replaced Wladyslaw Gomulka as First Secretary of the ruling Polish United Workers’ Party. Poland began borrowing from other nations and amassed considerable debt. Strikes and work stoppages were frequent until the Gdańsk Agreement of 1980. The authoritarian government of Poland declared martial law in December 1981, and imposed drastic restrictions until July 1983. Numerous labor leaders were imprisoned and some were killed. Eventually, the All-Poland Alliance of Trade Unions stabilized the trade organizations. Communism fell in Poland in 1989. Lech Wałęsa, who had served as chairperson of Solidarity and been imprisoned himself, became the first freely-elected president of Poland since the 1920s. In 1999, Poland became a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) along with the Czech Republic and Hungary.
Scope and Content
The Poland Subject Files contain periodical clippings, reports, manuscripts, bibliographic references, and unofficial publications. They range from 1947 to 2002 with some undated. The bulk ranges from 1960 to 1989, with emphasis on government, state policy, martial law, oppression, violence, censorship, international relations, opposition movements, dissidents, religion, and publications. Notable topics include, but are not limited to, Pope John Paul II’s visits to Poland and the opposition movement Solidarity.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the Poland materials in files organized by specific categories and denominations. This original filing system has been largely preserved. Unprocessed materials which the Keston Center received in no particular order are arranged thematically and chronologically.
The Poland Subject Files are arranged in two series: I. General and II. Denominational
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 14.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Glemp, Josef.; John Paul II, Pope, 1920-2005 -- Travel -- Poland.; Popieluszko, Jerzy, 1947-1984.
Subjects (Organizations)
Catholic Church -- Poland -- Clergy.; Catholic Church -- Poland
Places
Poland -- Church history -- 20th century.; Poland -- History -- 1945-; Poland -- Politics and government -- 1945-1980.; Poland -- Politics and government -- 1980-1989.; Poland -- Politics and government -- 1989-; Poland -- Social conditions -- 1945-
Subjects
Antisemitism -- Poland.; Atheism -- Poland.; Christianity -- Poland.; Christianity and atheism.; Christians -- Poland.; Communism and Christianity -- Catholic Church.; Communism and Christianity -- Poland.; Freedom of religion -- Poland.; Human rights movements -- Poland.; Jews -- Poland.; Martial law -- Poland.; NSZZ "Solidarno" (Labor organization); Papal visits -- Poland; Persecution -- Poland.; Political persecution -- Poland.; Political prisoners -- Poland.; Propaganda, Communist -- Poland.; Religion and state -- Poland.; Religious education -- Poland.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Samizdat.
- General Subject Files, 1947-2001, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series includes historical background, important individuals, governmental structure, martial law, oppressive practices, censorship, international relations, and opposition movements.
  - History. General, 1966-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History. Auschwitz, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History. Katyn, 1970-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History. Katyn. Sikorski, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History. Pre-1945, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History. Post-1945, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History: Post-1946, 1967-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Individuals, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - State. Government. Nationhood (1 of 2), 1957-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - State. Government. Nationhood (2 of 2), 1957-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Identity, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Minorities, 1965-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - National Minorities. Ukrainians, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Elections, 1965-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dissident Pronouncements on Elections, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Individuals (Government) (1 of 5), 1978-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Individuals (Government) (2 of 5), 1974-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Individuals (Government) (3 of 5), 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Individuals (Government) (4 of 5), 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Individuals (Government) (5 of 5), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Military Affairs, 1947-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Martial Law in Poland: ANALYSIS, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Martial Law in Poland: ANALYSIS, 1982 January (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Martial Law in Poland: ANALYSIS, 1982 March-November (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Martial Law in Poland: ANALYSIS, 1983 January-December (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Martial Law in Poland: ANALYSIS, 1984, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Martial Law in Poland: Chronology, 1981 December (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Martial Law in Poland: Chronology, 1982 January-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Martial Law in Poland: Chronology, 1983 March-1984 April (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Espionage, 1969-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Emigration, 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Law. Constitution, 1969-2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Constitution, 1973-1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - State police. State security organs, 1965-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Official documents. Pronouncements. Suppression of the Opposition Movements, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1968-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1984-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Physical Violence, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Physical Assault. Murder, 1977-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fines, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Trials, 1968-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Imprisonment, 1966-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Censorship, 1973-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Censorship: Authorities documents, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Censorship, 1964-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Censorship. Public Reaction, 1979-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Oppressive Practices towards "Solidarity", 1980 June-December (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Oppressive Practices towards "Solidarity", 1980 January-August (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Oppressive Practices towards "Solidarity", 1987 October-1988 August (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Provocation, 1979-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Psychiatric Detention, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - House Searches. Confiscation of Literature and Property, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - International Relations. The West and the World, 1965-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Relations. Eastern Bloc, 1966-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - International Relations. Germany, 1965-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - International Relations. Soviet Union, 1981-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - International Relations. Vatican, 1972-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - International Relations. Poland-Vatican in Pro-Government Catholic Press, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Foreigners. Smuggling. Personal Contacts, 1965-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Peaceful Coexistence. Exchanges. Detente, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Belgrade Conference, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Helsinki Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Madrid Conference, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Western reactions. Interventions. Pronouncements. Protests. Criticism (1 of 2), 1957-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Western reactions. Interventions. Pronouncements. Protests. Criticism (2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dissidents and the West. Official Western Reaction to the Opposition in Poland. Western Public Reaction to the Opposition in Poland, 1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dissidents and the West. Official Western Reaction to the Opposition in Poland. Western Public Reaction to the Opposition in Poland, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dissidents and the West. Official Western Reaction to the Opposition in Poland. Western Public Reaction to the Opposition in Poland, 1981-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - International Incidents, 1969-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International, 1968-80 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - State Visits, 1964-1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - State Visits. Eastern Bloc, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Analysis of Events, 1980 January-July (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Analysis of Events, 1980 August (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Analysis of Events, 1980 September-October (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Analysis of Events, 1980 November-December, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Solidarity Movement. Analysis, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Solidarity Movement. Analysis, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Chronology of Events. Solidarity, 1980 February-October (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Chronology of Events. Solidarity, 1980 November (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Chronology of Events. Solidarity. Information from Poland, 1980 November (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Chronology of Events. Solidarity, 1980 December-1981 January (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Support of Human Rights Dissidents, 1961-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Support of Human Rights Dissidents Abroad, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Activities Disapproved by the State, 1980 July (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Activities Disapproved by the State, 1980 August (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Activities Disapproved by the State, 1980 September (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Activities Disapproved by the State, 1981 June (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities., 1968-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities, 1979-1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dissidents. Protests. Illegal Activities, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Experts within Solidarity, 1980-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Individual Dissidents. A-B, 1970-1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Individual Dissidents. Chojecki, Miroslaw, 1979-1980, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Individual Dissidents. C-K, 1970-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Individual Dissidents. Kolakowski, Leszek, 1969-1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Individual Dissidents. Kowalska, Anka. Kozlowski, Jan., 1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Individual Dissidents. Kuron, Jacek, 1966-1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Individual Dissidents. L-M, 1969-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Individual Dissidents. Michnik, Adam, 1977-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Individual Dissidents. N-S, 1977-1989, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Individual Dissidents. Z-W, 1979-1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Individual Dissidents. Walesa, Lech, 1980-1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Individual Dissidents. Walesa and Pope John Paul II, 1980-1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Individual Dissidents. Walentynowicz, Anna, 1981-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Protests. Hunger Strikes. Demonstrations, 1956-1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Protests. Hunger Strikes. Demonstrations, 1980-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Human Rights Groups, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Appeals to the West, 1976-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Dissident Groups, 1976-1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Political Opposition, 1976-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - KOMITET POROZUMIENIA NA RZECZ SAMOSTANOWIENIA NARODU, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Robcio Publications, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - KOR. KSS-KOR, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - KOR. KSS-KOR, 1978-1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - KOR. KSS-KOR, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - KOR. KSS-KOR. Publications, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Student Self Defense Committee. Student Solidarity Committee, 1972-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Student Self Defense Committee. Student Solidarity Committee. Publications, 1977-1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ruch Mlodej Polsky, 1979-1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Independent Student Union, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - PPN. Polish Independence Agreement and Publications, 1978-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Freedom & Peace, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Polish Amnesty International Group, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - KPN. Confederation of Independent Poland, 1980-1983, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - KPN. Confederation of Independent Poland. Publications, 1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Treatment of Political Prisoners, 1980-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Farmers Self-Defense Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Farmers Self-Defense Committee. Publications, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Free Trade Union, 1978-1979, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Free Trade Union. Publications, 1979, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - TKN, 1977-1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - TKN. Publications, 1978-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - DIP, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Independent Political Group. Publications, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Peasant University. Publications, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Defectors, 1965-1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Solidarity "Statements", 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Solidarity. Documents, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Solidarity. Books, 1979-1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Solidarity. Trips, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Solidarity in the West, 1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Solidarity under Martial Law, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Solidarity. Workers. Strikes. Action, 1981 January-February (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Solidarity. Workers. Strikes. Action, 1981 March-June (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Solidarity. Workers. Strikes. Action, 1981 July-December (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reaction to Polish Crisis in Soviet Union, 1980 July-September (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reaction to Polish Crisis in Soviet Union, 1980 October-December (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reaction to Polish Crisis in Soviet Union, 1981 January-May (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reaction to Polish Crisis in Soviet Union, 1981 June-December (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reaction to Polish Crisis in Soviet Union, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Bloc Reactions to Polish Crisis, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - West and US Reactions to Polish Crisis, 1980-1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - East German Press. General Coverage on Poland, 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - West German Press. General Coverage on Poland, 1980 August-December (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - West German Press. General Coverage on Poland, 1981 January-July, 1987 January (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Peace and Freedom Movements, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - PPN.Polskie Porozumienie Nepodleglosciowe, 1978 November-1980 February (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - AS Warszawa, 1981 March-May (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - AS Warszawa, 1981 May-June (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bratniak, 1977 October-1979 February (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bratniak, 1979 March-August (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Biuletyn Informacjny No. 1-21/22, 1976 September-1978 July (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Biuletyn Informacjny No. 23-26, 1978 August-November (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Biuletyn Informacjny No. 26-2/28, 1978 December-1979 March (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Biuletyn Informacjny No. 3/29-4/30, 1979 May-June (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Biuletyn Informacjny No. 5/6(31/32), 1979 July-September (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 7(33), 1979 September-October (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 8(34), 1979 November-December (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 1(35), 1980 January-February (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 2(36), 1980 March-April (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 3(37), 1980 May (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 4(38), 1980 June (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny No. 5(39)-6(40), 1980 July-September (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Biuletyn Informacynjy No. 7(41), 1980 October-November (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny Komitetu Samobrony Chlopskiej Ziemi Grojeckiej, 1979 November (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Biuletyn Dolnoslaski, 1978 July-1984 May (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Droga, 1978 June-1979 July (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Gazeta Polska, 1979 February-November (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Glos, 1977 October-1978 September (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Glos, 1978 October, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Glos, 1978 November-December (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Glos, 1979 January-May (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Glos, 1980 January-August (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Gospodarz, 1978 February-1979 June (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Index, 1979 May-August (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Katyn Institute, 1980 Feb. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Artisan's "Solidarity", 1981, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Rural Solidarity, 1980-1983, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Dissident Cultural Activity. Unofficial Art, Theater, and Film, 1976-1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Religion. History, 1957, 1973-1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Church-State Relations, 1972-1983, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Law & Religion, 1928, 1936-1947, 1987, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - International Conferences hosted by the Christian Social Association, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Western Reactions etc. re: Religion, 1957, 1871, 1980-1986, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Delegations from Poland Visit Abroad, 1978-1980, 1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Visits (Interdenominational) from Foreign Delegations, 1966 - 1981, 1987 - 1992, 1996, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Visits (Interdenominational) from Foreign Delegations. Graham, Billy, 1966, 1978, 1979, 1981, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Church Dissidents, 1980-1988, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - State of War and After (1 of 2), 1981-1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - State of War and After (2 of 2), 1981-1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - PR Church and Solidarity (1 of 2), 1980-1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - PR Church and Solidarity (2 of 2), 1980-1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Church Involvement in Workers Unrest. The Episcopate: The Pope (1 of 2), 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Church Involvement in Workers Unrest. The Episcopate: The Pope (2 of 2), 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Christian Theological Academy (CHAT), 1977, 1980, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Help for Poland. International Food and Medical Aid, 1981 - 1998 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Statistics on Churches and Church Membership, 1972-1985, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Religious Broadcasting Information Services from the West, 1970, 1976-1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Communism and Christianity. Communism and Other Religions. Christian-Marxist Dialogue, 1971-1987 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Ecumenical Movement (1 of 3), 1965, 1971-1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ecumenical Movement (2 of 3), 1965, 1971-1988 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Ecumenical Movement (3 of 3), 1965, 1971-1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Purges. Ideological Deviation from the Communist Party Line, 1968-1971, 1976-1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Communist Party's "Opposition Movement." Reformists. Hardliners, 1977, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - History of the Party. United Workers Party, 1975-1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - History of the Party. United Workers Party. Gomulka, Wladislaw, 1969-1976 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Ideology. Philosophy. Communism. Morality, 1965-1966, 1976-1988, 1999, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Polish Ecumenical Council, 1978-1986, 1990, 1998, 2000, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Religious Literature, 1971-1987, 1990 - 1994 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The Bible Society in Poland, 1944-1997 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny "Solidarność." Akademia Forlnicza Poznan, 1981 March 16 - 1981 October 26, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Serwis Informacyjny "Solidarność" UAM - Poznan, 1981 March, 1981 November 11 (Box 16, Folder 15)